MUHAMMAD NUR HIDAYAT

Full Stack Engineer

Jakarta Utara, DKI Jakarta

(+62) 812-9840-8698 danimnh4@gmail.com

PROFILE

I'm a skilled and dynamic software engineer with experience in full-stack development especially on front-end development. I believe that understanding both aspects of web development is important for creating effective and efficient solutions. By having experience in both areas, I'm able to create holistic solutions that consider both the technical and user-facing aspects of a project. This allows me to create applications that are not only functional, but also user-friendly and visually appealing.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

❖ Jr. Fullstack Engineer II, Spacetoon Go - Cloudthought Ltd. ______ Dec 2022 — Present

- Migrated data from various databases using Airbyte, ensuring smooth data transfer between systems.
- Successfully moved data from Clevertap to Clickhouse, optimizing the database for faster query processing.
- Managed the company's own Data Lake using Clickhouse, maintaining data accuracy and integrity.
- Provided Metabase for business team, enabling them to generate customized reports and analytics.
- · Prepared an ecommerce platform to sell toys for adults and kids using WordPress and Woocommerce with customized themes, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- · Maintain cloud infrastructure on Hetzner, managing services made by coworkers on Docker, and manage security measures such as VPS firewalls and service-specific security to ensure seamless and secure operations.

❖ Jr. Fullstack Engineer, Couda - Cloudthought Ltd. Oct 2021 — Present

London, UK

- Develop and maintain internal and external tools for a code learning web application using Svelte and JavaScript, enabling users to view and participate in coding lessons.
- · Managing bundles using Rollup.js to bundle specific parts of lessons, enabling dynamic learner lesson views on Svelte. Reducing bundle size server on mobile app.
- Lead and handle mobile app webview to Javascript communication using Javascript channels, ensuring seamless and efficient data exchange.
- Writes comprehensive curriculums and lessons on HTML, CSS, and Javascript to provide a structured, engaging, and interactive learning experience for our potential market
- · Implement version control of the curriculum structure and codebase using GitHub, ensuring code consistency and tracking changes effectively.
- · Collaborate with other engineers in the team using Trello, facilitating efficient communication and task management

Bogor, Indonesia

- · Created a Progressive Web App for an Endangered Animal Identification App using ReactJS, providing users with an engaging and interactive experience.
- · Worked closely with the Ministry of Environment and Forestry of Indonesia to maintain teamwork and ensure data accuracy in the database.

Bogor

- · Started an e-commerce mobile app MVP to crawl the cheapest tech products among Indonesia's e-commerce using React Native with Expo for hybrid development using Typescript
- · Discussed and implemented project requirements with other team members including talking about ads, market, and features roadmap.
- Deployed React Native App to Playstore
- · Used Figma for design and prototyping

EDUCATION

♣ Institut Pertanian Bogor	Sep 2017 — Sep	2021
Bachelor		Bogor
 Graduated with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science from IF Studies blockchain as final year thesis, developing front-end for blosystem of shallots commodity using prototyping method. 	•	
SKII	LLS	
Docker	React	
Node.js	JavaScript	
MongoDB		
LANGU	JAGES	

English Highly proficient